Register of the Margo House Papers, 1973-1980
Wisconsin Historical Society
Margo House Papers, 1973-1980
House, Margo, 1928-
Eau Claire Mss BU; VBA 470
1.0 c.f. (1 record center carton) and 1 videorecording
Housed at the Area Research Center, William D. McIntyre Library, University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire; owned by the Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Papers of Wisconsin feminist Margo House pertaining to the founding of the Eau Claire chapter of NOW; her service on the Governor's Commission on the Status of Women, circa 1975-1979; the Wisconsin Feminists Project Fund, circa 1974-1977, a group which funded historical research projects and employment workshops related to women (House served as its president); and several educational programs aimed at sexism. The video is from the Governor's Commission convention of 1976.
Margo House was born in August 1928. She graduated from Bryn Mawr College, with a B.A. in Art History in 1949. After additional schooling, House worked for the Board of Regents at the University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire from 1965 to 1969; she also taught English there, as a faculty assistant, from 1968 to 1971. In 1977 House received her M.A. in Counseling from the University of Wisconsin-Stout. During the 1970's she was active in the women's movement in Wisconsin, serving on the state board of the League of Women Voters, as president of the Wisconsin Feminists Project Fund, and as state coordinator for the National Organization for Women. House also was a member of the Governor's Commission on the Status of Women until its disbanding in 1979.
The Margo House Papers are an alphabetically-arranged subject file documenting the many issues and organizations with which she was involved. They cover the years 1973-1980, with heaviest coverage on the latter years. It was during this time that many of the organizations with which House was involved were firmly established. The collection includes material concerning educational programs, both for schools and the workplace, which were sponsored by various women's groups. These programs, some of which were eventually utilized by the State of Wisconsin, sought to oppose discrimination and sexism: Women in Wisconsin History; Attitudes, Women, and Employment; Skilled Jobs for Women; and so on. Materials dealing with the National Organization for Women deal primarily with the Eau Claire chapter, with some assorted state-level information. The collection also contains correspondence between women's groups and state and local government agencies on a wide array of issues.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Dr. Helen Sampson, Eau Claire, Wisconsin, 1982. M82-346
Contents List
- Attitudes, Women, and Employment, Eau Claire Mss BU
  - Evaluations, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Proposals, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Staff memos, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Training materials, 1974; 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Unemployment issues, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Current Issues in Women's Equality, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Eau Claire National Organization for Women, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Equal Rights Amendment, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Feminist Advocacy Network, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Governor's Commission on the Status of Women
  - Clippings and financial, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Issue positions, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting information, 1975-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Convention video, 1976, VBA 470
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1979, Eau Claire Mss BU (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Local government issues, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Marital property reform, 1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- National Women's Conference, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Skilled Jobs for Women, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Skilled Training Improvement Program, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- State government issues, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Uncommon Lives of Common Women, correspondence and financial, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Wisconsin Feminists Project Fund
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - Financial, 1974-1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Meeting minutes, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Membership and organizational materials (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Wisconsin Women's Network, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Women, Historical Identity, and Challenge, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Women in Wisconsin History
  - Correspondence, 1974-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Progress Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Women's Educational Equity Act, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Miscellaneous, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)